Also called HTTP Box, tell the server. What action you want to perform? Think of them
as different types of requests. You can make the food most important methods. So basically
the first method will be get method you can see. In get method purpose what will be the
purpose? The purpose will be retrieve or get information from the server, okay. Example
when you type a website address and press enter, then when you click on a link, when
you search for something on Google. So this will be things which will be performed in
get request, right. Now let's say what will be the characteristics? So basically data
is visible in the URL like search, like push mark search equals to cats, right. See if
doesn't like doesn't change anything on the server and can be booked marked get cache
it by browser. So in real life, real life analogy will be looks like looking at the items
in a store window. You have just you are just being not buying, okay. Example like when
you are just looking are looking are shoes in Amazon. So that thing will be performed
in get request, okay. Get method request. Now let's let's talk about post method. So
basically what will be the purpose or post request? So basically send data to the server
to create or submit something, okay. So when you are doing login, okay submitting a login
form, creating a new social media post, uploading a file like changing your like changing
your first name or last name, okay. So submitting a contact form. So this will be things
with this will be done which will be in post method, okay. Now what will be the characteristics
in this post method? Data is data is hidden sent in the request request what if known
to URL can send large amounts of data not cashed by browser cannot be booked marked changes
something on the server, okay. And what will be the energy? Basically the analogy will
be handling a letter to a post office. You are sending something, okay. Example when you
are logged into a website your website username and password are sent via post, okay.
Now let me show you get and post request how it's real like in real life it will work,
okay. So let's say our example, let's take example, okay.
So I want to you can see, you can see there is a search button right. So I want to search
at something. So before searching anything we need to open that inspect tab here you can
see the inspect tab. Now you need to go to this network tab, okay. You need to this
network tab and just wait over here and before now, now type anything like which art do
you need. So I want canvas, okay. Let's see, yeah. When I did canvas here you can see
this request, see this request method will be which method you will be use it will be
used in post method, right. See, now let's see the our query what will be our query. See,
what we did search for canvas, right. See, this is basically a post method, okay. Where
request where data will be in. Okay. Now we need to just again and do inspect tab open
your network tab and let's go to this home or categories, let's go to this category, okay.
And here you can see, when we just take upon this category and we are grabbing some data
from server. So at that time we need get method, okay. We need get method, we can see get
method, now see the, yeah. Now let's see these posters, here you can see. So basically
this is the URL, see and here you can see the method request method, okay. Now let's
see this product, the show product, okay. Here you can see again we got this product in
get method, okay. So this is how get and post method works, okay. Now let's discuss
upon this put method. So purpose, what will be the purpose of this put method update
or replace existing information, okay. Let's say example updating your profile information
editing blog post changing your settings. Guys, how do you remember like when you are uploading
a profile dp or changing your profile dp at that time that request will be made in put
request, okay. When you are doing something like updating your information, okay. So at that
time this method will be a direct request method will be put method, okay. Now what will
be the kite status in this put method. So basically replaces the entire resource, okay. If
the resource doesn't exist, it can create it, okay. And what will the real life energy,
basically the real life energy will be something like replacing an old poster with new
one on our wall, okay. Now let's let's check where post will be happen browser or guest
book. So let's type, let's type test, okay and do see this is post method. Let's check
the profile, okay. So test. We need to enter the default credential and this sorry, okay.
Now we need to upload or we need to change this user info to test test, okay. Now let's
submit this form user info and it's also like the request method will be also in post method,
okay. See post method. So I think so over here there will be there will be no put method
will be here. So what we need to do, we just need to create an account over like, over
like, let's see Panasonic, login.
Okay. I see the issue. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay. It's asking me to enter the phone number. So I didn't, I didn't think so. We
need to use our phone number. So let's see. Over here.
I thought, like, send HTTPS test.com or let's say Google.com. Okay. Google.com. Send the data.
Oh, this is a basic API. So, so basically guys, we need to just create an account first,
okay. Then you need to go that your profile, okay. And during that profile, one light
tap over there in this profile, that profile, okay. And then before of any, like updating
your data to anything. So before of that, you need to just do inspect, okay. Then you need
to just open that network tab and then update your data from like John to test, okay. And
then update that information and then capture that request into your network tab and see
that that method that request method will be done in foot method. Okay. So and now, let's see
the delete, the delete method. Okay. So basically what will be the purpose in this delete method?
Like you, you already knew about delete, okay. Delete means a delete, delete a resource from
the web server, right. So example, let's take an example. So deleting, you need to, you
need to just delete your social media. So when you are doing, when you did each and every,
like you want to delete your Facebook profile, okay. Let's say. So at that time, you need
to verify your profile, like confirm your password, okay. And then you got a function,
which is the delete function, right. When you tap the delete function, so before you tapping
the delete function, just enable your inspect tab and then open your like network tab, okay.
Then tap upon that delete function and see that delete request will be done in delete method.
Okay. So removing, let's say, removing an item from your card, okay, that will be that
request also made it delete method, deleting your account again, it's same, it's same thing,
delete, delete method will be used and what will the kite sticks? Basically, the kite sticks
of this delete method permanently removes data cannot be done and done usually, okay.
Here at the understand, you can see the like methods, which will be the safe methods,
see that will be get put delete head option. So these are the methods, basically, okay.